Guide to the Charles Garside Jr. papers, 1953-1987 MS 421
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Charles Garside Jr. Papers
1953-1987
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Garside, Charles
MS 421
9 Linear Feet
Rice University Baker College material, teaching and History Dept. records, academic and scholarly correspondence, notes and drafts of books, articles, and lectures, as well as a quantity of Renaissance-Reformation subject files, document the faculty and scholarly activities of Charles Garside Jr. (1927-1987). These papers cover the period 1949 to 1987. Well versed in history, literature, music, and the arts, Garside's particular area of scholarly interest was the Renaissance and the Reformation, especially the relationship between the Reformation and the arts. In addition, the papers reflect Garside's heavy involvement in the residential college system as a Baker Executive Associate.
Biographical / Historical
Charles Garside was born in New York City on June 27, 1927. His father, Charles Sr., was a prominent New York Lawyer who, in 1947-49, chaired the state's first Commission Against Discrimination. The elder Garside died in November, 1964.
Garside was educated at St. Bernard's School for Boys and graduated from Phillips Exeter Academy in 1944. After service in the navy, he received his A.B. with honors from Princeton in 1950. One year later he received an M.A. from Columbia University, and in 1957 he was awarded a doctorate in history at Yale University. Between Columbia and Yale, Garside taught at Hotchkiss, a private secondary school in Connecticut.
Garside stayed on at Yale to teach as a member of the history department. Garside continued at Yale for almost a decade, moving up from Instructor to Associate professor. For three years he served as Director of Undergraduate Studies in History. In his time at Yale, he was also Assistant Master of Timothy Dwight College from 1961-1963 and was Executive Fellow of that college from 1963-1966. While at Yale Garside won wide acclaim for his scholarship, his eloquence as a speaker, and for his dedication to his students.
In 1966, when Garside left Yale for Rice, he was honored with a lifetime appointment as Associate Fellow of Timothy Dwight College, and the undergraduates endowed in his honor the Garside Cup. This award to be given to an outstanding senior who best exemplified his talents. One of the reasons Garside chose Rice was for its Ivy league style college system, a system Garside considered to be the only proper way to organize undergraduate living.
At Rice, Garside became a respected member of the faculty and furthered his reputation as a teacher whose focus was on his students. Garside achieved his full Professorship at Rice in 1978. Between 1973 and 1983, Garside's former students voted him five George R. Brown Awards, an award given annually for outstanding teaching. Members of Baker College at Rice, where he was an Executive Associate, honored him with the college's Service Award in 1970.
Well versed in history, literature, music, and the arts, Garside's particular area of scholarly interest was the Renaissance and the Reformation, especially the relationship between the Reformation and the arts. On this topic he was a renowned authority and he published many scholarly works including the books: "Zwingli and the Arts" in 1966 and "The Origins of Calvin's Theory of Music" in 1979. In 1974-75, Garside served as President of The American Society for Reformation Research. At the time of his death, Garside was working on a biography of John Calvin, the great Protestant reformer.
Garside died June 11, 1987, from complications associated with a stroke suffered in May of that year. Garside never married and at the time of his death was survived by his mother, brother, sister, and eight nieces and nephews.
Scope and Contents
Baker College material, teaching and History Dept. records, academic and scholarly correspondence, notes and drafts of books, articles, and lectures, as well as a quantity of Renaissance-Reformation subject files document the faculty and scholarly activities of Charles Garside Jr. (1927-1987). These papers cover the period 1953 to 1987. This represents roughly the second half of Garside's life or, from another perspective, from about the time he began his history Ph.D. work at Yale onward.
The papers bulk in the Teaching Records and Material series with Renaissance - Reformation subject files. These subject files can be further subdivided into two types: course specific subject files and non-course specific subject files. It is likely that these subject files were created for either of two needs: teaching purposes or as the result of research towards a particular book or article. It is also seems likely that if a subject file was created out of research purposes, once the book or article was published the file would be added to the rest, simply as more lecture source material. These subject files contain primarily handwritten and typed notes with some reprint material.
The papers bulk again in the series Scholarly Papers with notes, drafts, and correspondence concerning the many books, articles, reviews, papers, speeches and lectures published or presented by Garside. The papers also well represent the fact that Garside was a member of numerous history and Renaissance-Reformation oriented professional organizations/scholarly societies. Garside served as President of The American Society for Reformation Research for several years and much of the material here is correspondence.
The Garside papers contain very little of a personal nature. The most important material here being several folders of personal correspondence and some address books. Garside was a man of such high scholarship, so intensely devoted to teaching and university life, that if were not for original order it would be difficult to distinguish his personal correspondence from his scholarly correspondence. A few photographs, a number of recipes in a variety of handwritings and some poetry in Garside's handwriting provide some small insight into his nature and life outside the walls of academia.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Subjects (Persons)
Garside, Charles
Subjects (Corporations)
Baker College (Rice University)
- Series I: Teaching Materials, 26921
  - Subseries A: Course Materials, 27097
    - HIST 81-I Europe and the Reformation Exam, Jan 1958; 178334 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - HIST 85-I Europe and the Reformation, 1965; 178335 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - HIST 100 The Congress of Vienna Lecture I, c.a. 1968; 178336 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - HIST 100 Totalitarianism Lecture II, n.d.; 178337 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - HIST 100 French Revolution Lecture III, n.d.; 178338 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - HIST 100 Liberalism Lecture IV, n.d.; 178339 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - HIST 100 The Revolution of 1848 Lecture V, n.d.; 178340 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - HIST 100 The Revolution of 1848 Lecture VI, n.d.; 178341 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - HIST 100 The Contemporary World, n.d.; 178342 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - HIST 100 The Problem of Europe, n.d.; 178343 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - HIST 100 Science & Religion Lecture, n.d.; 178344 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - HIST 100 The Treaty of Versailles Lecture, n.d.; 178345 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - HIST 100 The Unification of Italy, n.d.; 178346 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - HIST 100 Course Planning Notes, n.d.; 178347 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - HIST 101 Fall Semester Syllabi & Exams, 1970-1974; 178348 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - HIST 101 The American Revolution I Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178349 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - HIST 101 The American Revolution II Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178350 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - HIST 101 The Christian Millennium: Cosmology Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178351 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - HIST 101 The Copernican Revolution Lecture & Notes, n.d.; 178352 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - HIST 101 The English Experience I Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178353 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - HIST 101 The English Experience II Lecture Notes, 1970; 178354 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - HIST 101 The Enlightenment Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178355 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - HIST 101 The French Revolution 1789, n.d.; 178356 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - HIST 101 The French Revolution: The Constitution of 1791 Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178357 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - HIST 101 The Greek Experiment I Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178358 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - HIST 101 The Greek Experiment II Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178359 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - HIST 101 An Ideology for Democracy: Christianity Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178360 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - HIST 101 An Ideology for Deomocracy: From Religion to Politics Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178361 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - HIST 101 The Newtonian Universe Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178362 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - HIST 101 Part of the Third World, n.d.; 178363 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - HIST 101 The Reformation Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178364 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - HIST 101 The Renaissance Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178365 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - HIST 101 Science in Society: China Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178366 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - HIST 101 Science in Society: Institutions for Science Lecture & Library of Congress Readings, n.d.; 178367 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - HIST 101 Science in Society: Islam Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178368 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - HIST 101 Science in Society: Spokesmen for Science Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178369 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - HIST 101 Sir Francis Bacon Selected Readings, n.d.; 178370 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - HIST 101A, 101B Statistics & Final Exams, 1971-1972; 178371 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - HIST 101A, 101B Syllabi & Registrar Correspondence, 1969-1970; 178372 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - HIST 101A Syllabi, Exams, & Course Notes, 1977-1979; 178373 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - HIST 101A The Vienna Settlement Lecture, n.d.; 178374 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - HIST 102B Class Notes, Handouts, & Readings, 178375 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - HIST 102B The Great Reversal Lecture, n.d.; 178376 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - HIST 102B Slide Descriptions & Notes, n.d.; 178377 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - HIST 102B Syllabi, Midterms, & Final Exams, 1971-1976; 178378 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - HIST 102B World War I & the Legacy of the Industrial Revolution Class Handouts, 178379 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - HIST 130 The Problems of the Renaissance, 1958; 178380 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - HIST 330 The Renaissance Exams, n.d.; 178381 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - HIST 331A&B The Two Reformations 1517-1598, n.d.; 178382 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - HIST 332 The Radical Reformation: Wittenberg Lecture, n.d.; 178383 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - HIST 332B The Two Reformations, n.d.; 178384 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - HIST 333 Course & Instructor Evaluations, Spring 1985; 178385 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - HIST 333A&B Europe & the Reformation Syllabi, 1975-1985; 178386 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - HIST 333 Luther Syllabi & Library Reading Lists, 1983, 1985, 1986; 178387 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - HIST 333 The Central Problem: Authority in the Church Lecture Notes & Annotated Reading, n.d.; 178388 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - HIST 333 Conciliar Program Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178389 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - HIST 333 The Course of the Reformation in Germany Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178390 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - HIST 333 the Crisis of Medieval Thought Lecture, 1969; 178391 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - HIST 333 Empire Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178392 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - HIST 333 German Material & Notes, n.d.; 178393 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - HIST 333 Luther Religious Experience Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178394 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - HIST 333 Luther the University Professor Handout & Annotated Copy, 178395 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - HIST 333 The 95 Theses Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178396 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - HIST 333 The Papacy & the Cannon Law Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178397 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - HIST 333 Papal Indulgences Lecture, 178398 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - HIST 333 The Peasant's War Annotated Reading, n.d.; 178399 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - HIST 333 Religious Freedom Potential Material, n.d.; 178400 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - HIST 333 The Religious Peace of Augsburg Lecture & Annotated Readings, n.d.; 178401 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - HIST 333 The Right of Resistance Reading, n.d.; 178402 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - HIST 333 The True Church in the Late Middle Ages Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178403 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - HIST 333 The Wittenberg Crisis I Timeline & Notes, n.d.; 178404 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - HIST 333 The Wittenberg Crisis II Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178405 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - HIST 333A Ozment's Lectures, n.d.; 178406 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - HIST 334A&B Calvin & Geneva 1509-1564 Syllabi & Exams, 1978-1979; 178407 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - HIST 464B Calvin & Geneva Syllabus, 1986; 178408 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - HIST 334 Bucer, Strosburg, & the Church Order Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178409 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - HIST 334 Calvin & Geneva Student Lecture & Reading Notes, 1983; 178410 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - HIST 334 Calvin & Religion Notes & Annotated Readings, n.d.; 178411 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - HIST 334 Geneva Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178412 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - HIST 335B Syllabi & Exams, 1981-1982; 178413 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - HIST 345 Art Psychology, n.d.; 178414 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - HIST 345 The Christian Revival, n.d.; 178415 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - HIST 345 Donatello, Terribilita, Petrarch, n.d.; 178416 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - HIST 345 Germany Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178417 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - HIST 345 Italy Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178418 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - HIST 345 Paideia/Humanities, n.d.; 178419 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - HIST 345 Patronage Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178420 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Hist 345 The Recovery of the Greek World Reading, Notes, & Handout, 178421 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - HIST 345 The Renaissance & Petrarch Lecture & Handouts, 178422 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - HIST 345A Classical Antiquity & Christianity Lecture X, n.d.; 178423 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - HIST 345A The Philogical Revolution, n.d.; 178424 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - HIST 345A The Recovery of the Greek World, n.d.; 178425 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - HIST 346A&B Reformation Europe 1517-1598 Exams, 1986; 178426 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - HIST 433 Bonilla Complete Course Notes, 1976; 178427 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - HIST 433 Italian Humanism in the 15th Century Detailed Course Notes, n.d.; 178428 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - HIST 433A&B Renaissance Humanism: From Petrarch to Machiavelli Syllabi, 1981-1982; 178429 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - HIST 433 Bouwsma: Changing Assumptions Reading, n.d.; 178430 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - HIST 433 Civic Humanism, n.d.; 178431 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - HIST 433 Classical Culture & Christianity the Problems, n.d.; 178432 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - HIST 433 Coluccio Salutati, n.d.; 178433 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - HIST 433 The Essential Elements of Scholastic Culture, n.d.; 178434 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - HIST 433 The Essential Unity of Classical Culture, n.d.; 178435 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - HIST 433 Ficino: Letter on the Platonic Tradition, n.d.; 178436 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - HIST 433 Francesco Petrarca, n.d.; 178437 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - HIST 433 General Introduction, n.d.; 178438 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - HIST 433 The Humanism of Alberti, n.d.; 178439 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - HIST 433 Internal Tensions in Humanism, n.d.; 178440 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - HIST 433 The Invasion of Italy, n.d.; 178441 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - HIST 433 Leonardo Bruni: The Cicero Novus, n.d.; 178442 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - HIST 433 Leonardo Bruni: The Laudatio & the History, n.d.; 178443 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - HIST 433 Machiavelli & the Militia, n.d.; 178444 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - HIST 433 Machiavelli's Political Thought, n.d.; 178445 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - HIST 433 Marsibo Ficino, n.d.; 178446 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - HIST 433 Michelangelo: David, n.d.; 178447 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - HIST 433 Michelangelo: The Medici Tombs, n.d.; 178448 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - HIST 433 The Milanese Crisis, n.d.; 178449 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - HIST 433 The Paduan Humanists, n.d.; 178450 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - HIST 433 Petrarch: The Letter to Livy, n.d.; 178451 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - HIST 433 Petrarch & Moral Philosophy, n.d.; 178452 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - HIST 433 Petrarch: Preface to the DeViris Illustribus, n.d.; 178453 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - HIST 433 Picos the Oration & the Conclusions, n.d.; 178494 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - HIST 433 Princeps Concordiae, n.d.; 178495 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - HIST 433 Religion & Rhetoric Lecture & Reading, n.d.; 178496 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - HIST 433 Renaissance Humanism Course Planning, n.d.; 178497 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - HIST 433 Some Pre-Conditions for Humanism, 178498 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - HIST 433 St. Augustine & Classical Culture, n.d.; 178499 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - HIST 434 Course & Instructor Evaluations, Spring 1985; 178500 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - HIST 434 The Codex of Justinian Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178501 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - HIST 434 Mos Docendi Italicus Notes, 178502 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - HIST 434 St. Augustine & the Christian, n.d.; 178503 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - HIST 434A&B Syllabus, Notes, & Exams, 1979-1983; 178504 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - HIST 434 Readings, n.d.; 178505 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - HIST 570/571 War & Society Plus Correspondence, 1969-1973; 178506 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - HUMA 360 Major Interpretations of the West Plus Correspondence, 1984-1985; 178507 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Subseries B: Course Proposals, 26922
    - Course Planning Outlines, n.d.; 178484 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Course Reading Lists, n.d.; 178485 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Art, History, & Ideas in Renaissance Florence Potential Course, n.d.; 178486 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Guest Lectures & Syllabi, n.d.; 178487 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Loose Notes HIST 360, 570, 434, 433, n.d.; 178488 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - New Course Ideas, n.d.; 178489 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Potential Articles to Reference in Lectures, n.d.; 178490 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Reformation One Semester Course Lectures, 1969; 178491 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Seminar #2: The Reformation - Four Fundamental Principles, 178492 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Seminar Syllabus & Maps, 1980; 178493 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Subseries C: Lectures, 178333
    - 15th Century Stage for Eurpoean Expansion Lecture, n.d.; 178508 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 18th Century Government & Society, n.d.; 178509 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Anabaptism Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178510 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Art, History, & Ideas in Renaissance Florence Reading & Notes, n.d.; 178511 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Brumi Lecture, n.d.; 178512 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Chinese Inventions Written for Garside, n.d.; 178513 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - The Christian Millenium: Society, Learning Lecture, Readings, & Notes, n.d.; 178514 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Classical/Christian View about History Plus Handouts, 178515 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Cosmic Order & the Great Chain of Being, n.d.; 178516 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - The Council of Constance, n.d.; 178517 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - The Enlightenment, n.d.; 178518 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Erasmus Notes, n.d.; 178519 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - The European Age Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178520 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Florence Lecture III, n.d.; 178521 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - France Lecture I, n.d.; 178522 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - French Revolution: The New Elements Lecture, n.d.; 178523 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Geneva: The Teachers, n.d.; 178524 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - General Knowledge of God, n.d.; 178525 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Guillaume Bude Lecture, n.d.; 178526 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Hal: Special Sessions, n.d.; 178527 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Historical Ideas, n.d.; 178528 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - History of Space, Astrology, & Time, n.d.; 178529 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - History of the Western Tradition Lecture, n.d.; 178530 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Humanism & Evangelism, n.d.; 178531 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Humanism Lecture Based on Hannah Gray, n.d.; 178532 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Humanist Educators, n.d.; 178533 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Imperialism Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178534 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Industrial Revolution I Lecture & Readings, 178535 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Industrial Revolution II Lecture & Readings, 178536 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Industrial Revolution: China Lecture & Readings, 178537 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Industrial Revolution: Nature Lecture & Readings, 178538 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - The Intellectual Revolution, n.d.; 178539 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Italy: Humanism, n.d.; 178540 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Karl Marx Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178541 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Legal Humanism & a Methodology of History, n.d.; 178542 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Lorenzo Ualla, n.d.; 178543 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Luther, the Church, & Current Events in Education Lecture, 1969-1972; 178544 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - The Lutheran Doctrine & Resistance to Authority Lecture & Readings, 178545 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Luther's Ethics, n.d.; 178546 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Luther's Religious Experience Handout & Annotated Copy, 178547 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Marxian Socialism Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178548 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - The Medici Tombs, n.d.; 178549 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Medieval Historical Thought, n.d.; 178550 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - The Medeival & Renaissance View of Man, n.d.; 178551 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Michelangelo's David: Portrait of a City Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178552 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Nationalism I Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178553 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Nationalism II Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178554 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Papacy & Empire, n.d.; 178555 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - The Pazzi Conspiracy, n.d.; 178556 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Phyllis Dean & the Industrial Revolution, 178557 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - The Platonic Academy& Ficino & Neo-Platonism, n.d.; 178558 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - The Problem of the Institutional Church in Luther, n.d.; 178559 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Reconciliation Notes, n.d.; 178560 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Reformation in Europe Lecture Schedule & Notes, n.d.; 178561 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Religion & Humanism in France, n.d.; 178562 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Religious & Political Context for African Expansion Lecture, n.d.; 178563 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Religious Shifts in Europe, n.d.; 178564 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Renaissance Art: The Family Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178565 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Renaissance & Christianity, n.d.; 178566 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Roman & Islamic Spain, n.d.; 178567 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - The Royal Council & Nobility, n.d.; 178568 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Science, n.d.; 178569 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Scotland Notes, 178570 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - The Third Europe: France & the Netherlands II, 178571 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - The Three Crises Lecture Notes, n.d.; 178572 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Transport & Demographic Revolution, n.d.; 178573 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - The Trinity Lecture & Reading Notes, n.d.; 178574 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Toward World War II Lecture & Readings, n.d.; 178575 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Valla & Politian, n.d.; 178576 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Venice Lecture III, n.d.; 178577 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Western European History 800-1715 Final Lecture, n.d.; 178578 (Box 3, Folder 81)
- Series II: Subject Files, 178330
  Scope and Contents Note